Young master.
二少爷
I ‘ve talked to
事情
your brother
我已经在电话里
on the phone.
告诉你哥哥了
You didn't pass the political check.
精英班需要通过政审
So you can't join the elite class.
你这次没通过
Someone else
所以那个名额
took the spot.
就换成其他人了
Although you were acquitted
魏岱擎这个事情啊
of Wei Daiqing's accusation,
最后虽然判你无罪
the school took it seriously.
但是学校考虑得比较多
The Chairman himself proposed
毕竟这个精英班
the opening of the elite class.
是委员长亲自提议办的
So,
所以
the political check is strict.
审查肯定会更严苛一些
I know.
我知道
Of course, you still have a chance.
当然也不是没机会了
But given that the aftermath of that event wears on,
现在风口浪尖上
It's better to stay cautious.
谨慎一点儿好
When it
等这个事情
blows over,
过去一段时间
I'll find a way for you.
我再替你想办法
What's more,
另外
Dad has talked
爸爸已经跟你们校长
with your principal.
打过招呼了
When you go to ocean training
下个学期
next semester,
远洋训练的时候
he'll make you Second Mate.
给你安排个二副的位置
Though you can't join the elite class,
虽然精英班进不去了
but
但是
you don't have to be a sailor,
至少不用去当水兵嘛
right?
是吧
What about the original Second Mate?
那原本的二副呢
What do you mean?
什么原本的二副
The one
就是我顶掉位置的
I'm going to replace.
那个人
We don't know him.
咱们又不认识他
Why bother?
你管他干什么
The school will
学校
take care of him.
会给他安排好的
You don't need to worry about him.
你就不用管了
Brother,
哥
do you remember
你还记得
I asked you
我刚去上海的时候
to help me get a position
托你帮一个
in the Fourth Station House
叫向远生的朋友
when I was in Shanghai?
去第四警察所
If I hadn't cut the line,
如果不是因为我插队
an officer's brother
去四所的
would have joined
本来应该是
the Fourth Station House.
另一个警官的弟弟
It seems, I always
我好像
take opportunities away from others.
总是在抢别人的时机
My father told me
我的父亲曾经说过
never
永远不要去
steal another's opportunity.
抢别人的时机
Because it would change
因为它改变的
more than
不仅仅是
our own life paths.
我们一个人的命运
But, I think the opportunity
我恰恰认为
belongs to
时机只属于
the people who can seize it.
能够抢到它的人
Opportunity makes
时机造就的是
geniuses
天才
and heroes.
英雄
It's bad luck
令人陷入泥潭的
that gets people in trouble.
只是厄运
From now on, no one is allowed
以后在华家
to mention Xiang Yuansheng
任何人都不能再提
in my house.
向远生这个名字
Help yourself.
来 咱们自己吃
Go on.
来
Take this.
吃菜
Have some fruits.
吃点水果
Why are you so behaved?
怎么坐得这么规矩呀
Like a visitor.
你是客人啊
Yeah,
可能是
I've been long gone.
太长时间没回来了吧
Mrs. Liu cleans your room every day
刘嫂每天给你打扫房间
and doesn't touch anything.
东西都没动过
The room is
你走的时候是什么样子
exactly as you left it.
回来就是什么样子
Give me your wallet.
钱包
What do you want?
干什么
Just give it.
快点儿 让你拿你就拿
At home,
回到家里
you have drivers
出门有司机
and servants at your service.
买东西有佣人
You don't need money.
你不需要用钱
I'll keep it for you
这些钱我先替你保管
and I'll give it back
等你回到学校
when you return to school.
我再还给你
In case you run away again.
免得你半路上又跑了
It's 160 silver dollars.
一共一百六十块钱
I want it back then.
记得还给我
When you are ready,
准备好了
I'll take you back to school.
我就送你回学校
Have some fruits.
吃点水果
Dad,
爸爸
are you heading for M.M.A.?
您回军政部吧
Hua Zhen is going back to school.
华桢也要回去了
I took time off to drop him off at school
我请了假
and will return later.
送他回学校我再回来
Take him for a haircut on the way.
路上带他去理个发
Look at him.
他现在这个样子
He doesn't look like a soldier at all.
哪像个军人
Remember not to cause any trouble
以后不要再
for your family
因为自己的事儿
with your personal issues.
给家里惹麻烦了
Zhen,
桢儿
I had Mrs. Liu prepared some food
我让刘妈准备了些吃的
and daily necessities.
和日用品
Your brother will
一会儿让你哥哥
take them with you.
给你一趟送过去
If you need anything,
你要缺什么
just call us.
就给家里打电话
Yes, mom.
知道了
One more thing.
还有件事儿
Mom,
妈
I'll tell him about it.
我跟他说吧
OK.
也好
Take care.
路上小心
Are you going to the barbershop?
去理发店吗
No.
不去了
People may mistake
不知道的还以为
Dad for your commanding officer.
爸爸是你的长官呢
Why,
你说说你
can't you care about him
你就不能偶尔地主动地
once in a while?
关心他一下吗
Say something nice.
说点儿好听的
He would return the care.
他也不至于这样 对吧
The communication between people
人和人之间的交流
is mutual.
就是有来有回嘛
I don't know what to say to him.
我不知道跟他说什么
Say whatever you want.
跟他随便聊聊天就行了
Whatever you said to me,
你跟我说什么
say that again to him.
就跟他说什么
I know.
我知道
When you were little,
小的时候
you didn't see him often.
你经常见不到他
He was on a war.
那个时候打仗
Dad took me with him.
爸爸带着我
Mom had to take care of family elders.
妈妈要照顾两边的父母
They got no choice
把你留在家里
but kept you at home alone.
也是没有办法的事情
Noted?
对吧
You know what?
其实你知道吗
Before I went to Shanghai,
这次我去上海之前
Dad talked to Chief Tong
爸爸亲自给佟参谋长
on the phone for an hour.
打了一个小时的电话
Do you think
你以为我想延后三天
I was able to postpone the trial for three days?
就能延后三天吗
You're the Secretary.
你是侍从室秘书
Of course you can.
怎么不能
Let me finish.
别打岔
I'm being serious.
跟你说正经的呢
I just don't know
我就是不知道
what to talk to him.
能跟他聊什么
When I was a kid,
小时候呢
I wished he would stay at home.
盼着他能在家
Now, things turned out quite the opposite.
现在如果家里
If me and him at home,
只有我和他的时候
I will feel uncomfortable.
反倒觉得不自在
I'd rather stay in my room
我宁肯待在房间里
all day
一整天
and not see him.
不跟他打照面
Have a smoke.
抽根烟吧
I don't smoke.
我不抽烟
I thought you learned to smoke
我以为你这次去上海
in Shanghai.
什么都学会了呢
It will be all right.
没事儿
After your graduation,
等你从学校毕业回到家
you have enough time to get along well with him.
住一段时间就行了
We are family.
家里人
Family is complicated.
没有那么多复杂的
Well.
对了
One day, I accompanied Mom to the home of
前几天我陪妈妈
Vice President Jia of the Executive Office
去行政院贾副院长家
to play mahjong.
打麻将
His granddaughter was there.
他的孙女也来了
She graduated from Ginling College.
金陵女子大学毕业的
Do you know her?
你认识吧
Do you remember her?
有印象吗
No.
没有
Shall I
那我给你
introduce you to her.
介绍认识认识呗
You may want to write to her
你在学校可以给她
at school.
写写信什么的
No, thanks.
不用了
I don't like to write letters.
我不爱写信
Don't be so absolute in what you say
话先别说得那么绝
before
那是因为你还没有见过
you meet her.
她长什么样子
I can't remember faces.
我记不住长相
You must be thinking about
还想着那个
the policewoman in Shanghai.
上海女警察呢吧
Miss Luo told me
听骆小姐跟我说啊
you talked a lot that night.
你们那天晚上聊了很多
You went from small talk
从家长里短
to ideals.
到人生理想
I was shocked.
我听完之后非常地震惊
If I'm right, except for me,
除了我
you never talk so much
好像你还没有和任何人
to any other people, right?
聊过这么多话呢吧
And
怎么了
Do you hit it off well?
你们很投机吗
Did she say that?
她说我们很投机
In my opinion,
在我看来啊
the intimacy between people
人和人之间的亲密关系
begins with small talk.
就是从聊废话开始的
About Vice President Jia's granddaughter,
刚才在路上跟你提到的
whom I mentioned on the way,
贾副院长的孙女
Mom attempted
出门的时候
to tell you about her
妈妈本来就想
before we left.
自己跟你说
Our parents have arranged
家里都已经决定
your marriage to her.
让你和她定亲
Brother,
哥
are you kidding me?
你开玩笑的吧
Vice President Jia and Dad
爸爸和贾副院长
had a deep discussion
已经仔细地讨论过
about your future.
你的未来应该怎么样
Vice President Jia
贾副院长
needs our support.
需要我们家的支持
You
而你呢
need a backer
在党内也需要
in the Party.
其他的靠山
So they have
所以长辈
arranged
已经把你们这门婚事
your marriage.
定下来了
Vice President Jia and Dad
爸爸和贾副院长
discussed my future?
讨论我的未来
Hua Zhen,
华桢
I think
我也认为
you need the marriage,
你需要这门婚事
especially because of where you are.
尤其是你现在的处境
Luo Minmin
骆珉敏
is simple and nice.
是一个单纯的好女孩儿
But she is
可是就是因为她
too simple and too ordinary.
太简单 太平常了
You will not have a future.
你们不会有未来
Brother,
哥
I haven't even met
我甚至都
Vice President Jia.
没见过贾副院长
How could they
他们就这么
discuss my future
讨论我的未来
and decide my life?
决定我的人生啊
Your life
你的人生
has already been planned.
不是早已经规划好了吗
You are going to
你是要成为
assist the Chairman
委员长身边的
in building a Revolutionary Navy.
革命新海军的人
Your romance
况且你和骆珉敏
with Luo Minmin
那点儿假日恋情
is like a spring dream
人似秋鸿来有信
that leaves no trace.
事如春梦了无痕
Your romance in summer
夏日的这点儿浪漫
will disappear
一过去
before winter
走不到冬天
comes.
就什么都不剩了
All right.
好了
Remember to call home.
记得多给家里打电话啊
Do you remember these photos?
这些照片你还记得吗
This photo
这张照片
was taken by a reporter
是救国会的一名记者
of the National Salvation Organization.
拍下的
You know the person on the right.
右边这个你很熟悉
Tan Shiyuan, the Deputy Director.
公安局副局长谭施远
The identity of the man on the left
左边这个拿酒杯的男人
with the wine glass remains unknown.
还不清楚身份
The man in the middle is Nakamura Naoki.
中间这个叫里见直树
He's running
他在上海经营一间
Hongji Benevolent Society in Shanghai.
叫弘济善堂的慈善堂
And
而且
he was rated as a law-abiding citizen
被上海公安局评过
by the Shanghai Public Security Bureau.
遵纪守法好市民
It was published in the newspapers
谭施远给他
when Tan Shiyuan gave him
颁奖章的时候
the reward.
还登过报纸
I remember that news.
这条新闻我记得
Police officers often go to
弘济善堂门口
Hongji Benevolent Society
经常有警察过去
to keep the refugees in order.
维持难民的秩序
They were sent by Feng Guangyun.
都是冯广云派去的人
The photo was shot by a Shenbao reporter.
拍摄者是《申报》的记者
His name is Peng Ganwen.
他叫彭甘文
We just got the information
组织刚刚得到消息
that he and his wife, Yao Xiulin,
他和他的妻子姚修林
have disappeared.
接连失踪了
It may have something to do with
这很有可能和他发现
Tan Shiyuan and the Japanese.
谭施远勾结日本人有关
The organization ordered us
现在组织把找人的任务
to locate them.
交给了我们
According to intelligence,
根据组织的情报
Feng Guangyun of the Shiliupu Station
十六铺分局的冯广云
may have something to do
很有可能
with it.
与这件事情有关
You need to
所以你得想办法
get into the station
潜入分局
and find
在他身边
concrete evidence and
找到更确切的线索
probe into his real intentions.
探一探虚实
Considerate
我一定会完成
it done.
组织的任务
Stay safe.
注意安全
No worries.
放心
It's freezing in here.
冷死了这里
It's about closing time.
检查完这片就下班了
Hurry up.
抓紧时间
They don't even turn off the lights.
你说这些人连灯都不关
Shit in their heads.
脑子想什么呢一天到晚
Did you lock it?
锁好了吗
I did.
锁好了
This.
这个
Let's go.
走啊
Let's go get a drink.
走 找个地方喝点去
Can't wait.
喝点就喝点
You got me drunk last time.
上次被你灌趴下了
I will get you drunk today.
我今天晚上非把你灌倒
Cleaner,
那个拖地的
remember to turn off the lights.
记得关灯啊
The organization was right.
组织判断得没错
I found Mrs. Peng's medical record
我在冯广云的办公室
in Feng Guangyun's office.
找到了彭太太的病历
He must
看来冯广云
be part of it.
确实跟这件事情有关
What is
我们接下来的任务
our next task?
是什么
Mr. Peng is a member of the NSO.
彭记者是救国会委员
He writes news
他平日里
and collects stories
负责给《申报》撰写新闻
for Shenbao Newspaper.
收集素材
He discovered the relation of Hongji Benevolent Society
偶然间调查起弘济善堂
and Nakamura Naoki by accident.
和里见直树
The NSO feared
现在救国会也担心
he was murdered.
他是不是已经出事了
What else
除了拍完
did he take in his photo shots
那三人的照片
besides the three?
他还拍到了什么
He gave the photo
他就是把这一张照片
to the National Salvation Organization.
交给了救国会
And had been to
然后去过几次
the Shiliupu Wharf several times.
十六铺码头
Before he reported to
但他还没有
the National Salvation Organization,
跟救国会碰上面
he disappeared.
他就失踪了
No one knows
所以没有人知道
what happened to him
他到底在码头上
at the wharf.
发生了什么
Superiors want you to investigate
上级希望你从警察内部
from inside.
调查一下线索
I will put you
所以我会想办法
in the Criminal Investigation Department,
把你安排进刑警科
lurking beside Feng Guangyun.
潜伏在冯广云的身边
The Shiliupu Wharf
毕竟十六铺码头
is Feng Guangyun's territory.
是冯广云的地盘
It's safer
这样对你
for you
对四所
and the Fourth Station.
都更安全
Got it.
知道
This is for you.
这是给你的
For me?
这个 给我的
Yes, it's your tuition.
对 这是学费
We can't keep meeting each other
我们不能总在这里
in secret.
偷偷见面
People will get the wrong idea.
容易让人误会
What wrong idea?
误会什么
Bro,
哥哥 哥哥
buy a flower for the lady.
给姐姐买束鲜花吧
No, thanks.
不用了 小妹妹
She is beautiful.
姐姐这么漂亮
Buy one for her.
给她买一束吧
Here you are.
这个给你
Thank you, Miss.
谢谢姐姐
What a coincidence.
这也太巧了吧
Now you see it.
现在知道误会什么了吧
Me and you?
我们应该不能吧
Yeah, that's not going to happen.
我当然知道我们不可能
But we can't always meet
但是我们确实不能
in the same place.
一直在一个地方见面
I teach French
我平时呢
in the French Concession
会在法租界教会
church.
当法语老师
It's a place open to everyone
那些华捕啊 普通百姓
and Chinese police men are frequent there.
都可以去
You go there for classes.
到时候你就来这里上课
But I have no knowledge of French.
可是我一点基础都没有
That's why you should come.
所以你才有来的理由啊
You can say
对外你就说
that you went to learn French
你要跟法租界的人
to deal with people
打交道
in the French Concession.
实在太不方便
It's a safer way
这也是我们
for us to meet.
更安全公开见面的方式
Got it.
知道了
Here's your tuition
所以这是你的学费
and teaching aids fee.
还有教学用具费
Don't be late
下周来上课的时候
for next week's class.
不准迟到
I have to go.
走了
Do you want this?
这个你还要吗
It's yours now.
送给你
1, 2, 1.
一二一
1, 2, 3, 4.
一 二 三 四
I can't hear you.
没吃饭吗中午
1, 2, 1.
一 二 一
1, 2, 3.
一 二 三
That's it.
就这个
Do you have an eye for beauty?
你们这什么审美啊
Hua Zhen,
华桢
tell them.
来 你评评理
Look.
你看看
How is this girl?
我这姑娘怎么样
Come on.
不是
He's never held a woman's hand.
他连女人手都没牵过
It's useless to ask him.
你问他干吗呀
Right?
是吧
Hua Zhen,
华桢
what kind of girl do you like?
你到底喜欢什么样的呀
Yeah, do you have a photo?
是啊 有没有照片
Show us.
拿出来给大家看一看
Letter collecting!
收信了收信了收信了啊
Hurry up.
要寄信的可抓紧了
I got one.
我有 我有
Be quick.
来 快点
On my way.
好 走了啊
Anyone home?
有人吗
How can I help you?
你好 请问你有什么事
I want to report a missing person.
我要报警
My husband's name is Peng Ganwen.
我丈夫叫彭甘文
He's a reporter.
他是一名记者
About half a month ago,
大概半个多月前吧
he asked me to move
他让我一个人
to the hotel alone.
从家里搬去客栈住
And I'd never reach him ever since.
之后我就联系不上他了
You know
你也知道
as a reporter,
做记者的
he often discloses
经常会曝光一些
someone else's news.
不利于别人的新闻
I'm afraid
我担心
that he's in trouble.
他遇到什么危险了
Disclosing news?
对别人不利的新闻
Do you know what news
那您知道您丈夫
is your husband reporting?
现在在报道什么新闻吗
He's composing
他在写一篇
a report about refugees
有关于难民的报道
and now collecting material.
正在准备素材
Some days ago,
前段时间
he visited Shiliupu Wharf
去过几次十六铺码头
and took some pictures.
拍了些照片
OK,
好
I've written down your words.
您说的我都记下来了
We will
明天一早
enter investigation procedure tomorrow.
我们就立马立案
By the way,
对了
can you leave your address?
方便留下您的住址吗
No.5, Shiliu Lane, Jifu Road.
吉福路十六弄五号
What should I call you?
怎么称呼
Just call me Mrs. Peng.
就叫我彭太太吧
Got it.
好
If you recall
那要是您
any detail about the case,
再想起什么情况
report to the Fourth Station.
可以随时来四所找我
If it's not working hours,
要是 不是上班的时间
come to find me at my home.
你也可以去我家找我
I'm Luo Minmin,
我姓骆 骆珉敏
living at No.39,
住在南市西华弄
Xihua Lane, Nan District.
三十九号
Luo's photo studio,
你要是看到骆记照相铺
is my father's property.
那就是我家
Thank you, Officer Luo.
谢谢你骆警官
Never mind, goodbye.
好 您慢走
Mrs. Xu, letter from your son.
徐婶 您儿子的信
My son wrote me a letter again.
我儿子又来信了
Officer Luo.
骆警官
Any letters for the station house?
我们四所的信呢
Yes.
有有有
I'm about to send you letters
正准备给他们送完
after delivering others.
再给你们送呢
Where are those lazybones?
那几个懒货呢
Why do you
怎么最近
get mails on your own recently?
都是你自己出来拿
They are
二白哥
still busy working.
他们还在忙
What are they working for?
他们有什么好忙的
Busy drinking tea and reading newspapers.
不是喝茶就是看报
Huang,
黄大哥
are these
我们四所的信
all the letters we get?
就都在这儿了吗
Yes.
对啊
I will double check
要不然
in post office.
我回邮局帮你们找找再
Never mind.
没事
Thank you Huang.
那谢谢黄大哥了
You're welcome.
客气
Director.
所长
They haven't come back from shopping.
这买菜还没回来
Hongfa,
鸿发
grab me some water.
给 给我倒杯水
OK.
好
I'm exhausted this morning.
这一上午给我折腾的
Oh my god.
我的天
Well,
对了
what do you want for lunch?
中午想吃什么
Let Director cook for us.
让所长给咱做
Anything will do.
我吃点儿啥都行
Minmin, what about you?
珉敏 想吃什么
Minmin.
珉敏
She's missing Yuansheng.
远生
I'll go on duty outside.
我出去出个警
We're going with you.
我们跟你一起
Together.
一块儿一块儿
Aren't you
你们
just coming back?
你们不是刚回来吗
You should
太累了
have a rest first.
喝口水休息休息吧
Are you tired?
你们累吗
No.
不累
See, we are good.
你看 都不累
Captain told me
队长跟我说了
we're recruiting new constables.
马上招新警员
He will assign
到时候安排一个
the greatest one
最优秀的
to be my partner.
和我做搭档
Don't worry.
你们不用担心我了
I can go on duty
我自己一个人出警
by myself.
没问题的
The greatest partner.
最好的搭档
Who else can be better than us?
还有比我们更优秀的吗
Nobody.
那不可能
Is there?
有吗
No.
没有 没有
I can't find anybody
比咱仨还优秀的人
better than us.
哪儿有啊
Nobody.
你上哪儿找
Nowhere.
对呀
Don't be still.
行了 别愣着了
Let's go.
走吧
We're the best.
比咱仨还优秀
Officer,
警官
Mr. Peng and his wife
你找彭先生两口子
are not living here.
他们家没人的
Do you know
那您知道
where had they gone?
他们家人去哪儿了吗
They just
他们哪
paid me rents for three months.
就给了我三个月的租金
But they
结果呢
only lived here for ten days
就住了十多天
and never came back.
人吧 就再也没回来
That's weird.
你说真奇了怪了
Why didn't you
那租户信息
register on tenant information?
怎么没登记啊
Officer,
警官
it's hard to
这来回更换租户信息
keep the book updated.
实在是太麻烦了
so I...
所以就
Just this time.
下不为例啊
We are from the Fourth Station.
我们是四所的
If the tenement comes back,
等租户回来
don't forget to inform us.
记得跟我们联系
OK.
好的呀 好的呀
Goodbye.
慢走啊
Take care.
慢走 慢走
Why do so many
你说这警察
policemen come here?
怎么都来了呀
Captain,
队长
I have something to report.
我有事情向你汇报
Do you know
你认不认识
a reporter named Peng Ganwen?
一个叫彭甘文的记者
What's wrong?
怎么了
His wife just reported
前几天他太太过来报案
his disappearance to us.
说他可能失踪了
These days
这几天
I've been working on it,
我一直在想办法调查
but still find no clues.
还没有找到有用的线索
Captain,
队长
have you been to the Shiliu Lane?
你去过十六弄吗
I had been there,
我确实是去过十六弄
but for household registration.
之前是去登记户口
I never heard about any reporter.
没听说过什么记者
I went there just know.
我们刚才又去了
But the landlord
结果听说
said they hadn't lived there
他们有段时间
for a while.
不住在那里了
So I feel strange.
所以我觉得有点奇怪
You?
你们
You, Erbai and others?
你跟二白他们
Did Mrs. Peng
彭太太留下
leave her contact information?
联系方式了吗
How to find her?
怎么找她
She only left an address.
就留下了一个地址
You leave it to me.
这事你别管了
I'll take charge of it.
我来查吧
OK.
好
Go ahead.
去吧
Superiors want you to investigate it
上级希望你从警察内部
as a member of police force.
调查一下线索
So I will put you
所以我会想办法
to Criminal Investigation Department
把你安排进刑警科
and get close to Feng Guangyun.
潜伏在冯广云的身边
After all, Shiliupu Wharf
毕竟十六铺码头
is under his control.
是冯广云的地盘
It'll be safer
这样对你
for both you
对四所
and the Fourth Station.
都更安全
I know.
知道
Left right left.
一二一 跑起来
One two three four.
一 二 三 四
Halt!
立定
Left face!
向左转
Here's all the letters
他寄的所有信件
he sent.
都在这儿了
They're to the same people.
都是给同一个人的
Burn it.
把它烧了吧
Mr. Hua
华秘书
If I may,
如果可以
please don't
以后请不要
make me do things
再让我做这些
irrelated to training.
和训练无关的事情
Thank you.
谢谢
Come in.
进
Master Hu, you want to see me.
胡教官 您找我
Brother.
哥
What are you doing here?
你怎么来了
To deliver daily necessities to you.
给你送点儿日用品
Brother,
哥
did you take a leave and came from Nanjing
你专门从南京请假过来
just to deliver me this stuff?
就是给我送日用品啊
Mum asked me to visit you.
妈妈让我来看看你
She got a plan for you
其实你上个假期啊
for your last vacation.
她给你做了很多的安排
But you
可是你呢
went to Shanghai.
跑去了上海
I've explained it to mother.
我已经和妈妈解释过了
I know.
好了好了
I'm not to blame you.
我不是来问罪的
No need to see me off.
你不用送了
My car's just over there.
我的车就在那儿
By the way,
对了
I want to ask
顺便问你一件事情
do you still have contact
你离开上海之后
with those polices of the Fourth Station
跟那个第四警察所的人
after leaving Shanghai?
还有过联系吗
No.
没有
Really don't?
真的一次都没有
Any phone calls?
电话也没打过
No.
没有
Brother,
哥
why do you
你怎么突然
ask?
想起来问这个
A reporter named Peng
有一个姓彭的记者
is missing.
找不到了
He's one of my
跟我一个好朋友
friends' relative.
算是亲戚关系
Now many people
现在不少人
are searching for him everywhere.
都在到处找他
I heard that this case
听说这件事情
was put on record
是在你以前
by the police station
待过的警察所
you worked for.
立的案
So I help him ask you.
所以托我问问
I'm sorry
那还真是
I can't help.
帮不上什么忙了
Do you have their
那你有他们谁的
contact information?
联系方式吗
I want to enquire more.
我再去问问看
Brother,
哥
you told me not to care
你叮嘱我不要再过问
about what happened in Shanghai.
上海的任何事儿
But you
怎么现在
are asking me now instead.
反倒你主动来问我
He is a good friend of mine,
这个朋友跟我关系不错
otherwise I wouldn't give a hand.
否则我也懒得帮这个忙
I really don't
我和那边
have any contact with Shanghai.
确实没有联系了
Got it.
好 我知道
Remember to study well
回去好好上课啊
and discipline yourself.
不许乱跑
Try the orange, quite sweet.
尝尝橘子 橘子挺甜的
Don't just eat apples.
别光吃苹果
Hua Zhen, thanks for your oranges.
华桢 谢谢你的橘子
Take it.
接着
Ermao, give me a break.
二毛 你可甭练了
Hua Zhen brought us some fruits.
人家带了水果 过来吃
Quiet.
你别说话
I ‘m almost done.
我还有十个就完了
Class Three,
三班的 三班的
your letters arrive.
信到了啊
Help me out.
帮我拿一下
Let me see.
我看看
This's mine.
这个是我的
Sun Ze,
孙泽
Got letters?
刚刚是不是来信了
Is there any letter for me?
有没有我的信啊
Here you are.
这儿呢 我给你拿了
Hua Zhen, no letters for you.
华桢 还是没你的
Where did you send
你之前那么多封信
all those letters?
往哪儿寄的
Maybe the post route is blocked.
会不会是邮路不通
So they were not received.
没寄到
Shanghai.
上海
No way.
不对啊
I sent a letter to my friend there before
我之前给我朋友寄的
and he received it.
都寄到了
You can call the post office
要不你给邮局打电话
and ask about it.
再问问
Left right left.
一二一 一二一
One two three four.
一 二 三 四
Hello.
喂
I want to make a long-distance call to Shanghai.
我要个长途 上海
Hello, this is Shanghai.
你好 这里是上海
Hello, please transfer the call
你好 帮我接
to the Fourth Station House
上海市公安局
under Shiliupu Police Station
十六铺分局
of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau.
第四警察所
Hongfa.
鸿发
Erbai.
白哥
Let's go to the Shisi Lane and check residence registration.
咱得去十四弄查户口吧
OK.
走
Let's go.
对对对
Captain, we'll go now.
队长 我们走了啊
Household check doesn't need baton.
查户口不用拿警棍
Captain,
队长
there's a scuffle at the Donghua Lane.
东华弄有人打架
I'm going there.
我要去看一眼
Be careful!
你自己注意安全啊
OK.
好
Wait for me.
等我一块儿
I'm going to the Station.
我正好去分局
Are you all going on duty?
这怎 怎么都走啊
Will you come back for lunch?
回来吃午饭不
No.
不回来了
Happy to be leisure.
乐得清闲
Director, everyone has gone.
所长 大家都出去了
Do we need someone to stay here?
要不要留一个人在所里
No.
不用
You'll come back soon.
又不是不回来了
I'll address some private affairs.
我去办点儿私事儿啊
Sorry sir,
对不起
the number you checked does not exist.
现在查询此号为空号
Doesn't exist?
空号
Yes.
对
The owner of an invalid number
空号要么是
may have moved
因为搬新地址了
or changed to a new number.
要么就是换新号码了
Could you please help me
那能麻烦你帮我查一下
check the new number of the Fourth Station House?
第四警察所的新号码吗
Sorry
对不起
I don't find a new registered number.
我没有查到新号码登记
But the telephone station was informed before
不过电话局接到过通知
that many police stations
年底有不少警察所
will log off their numbers
都会注销号码
because of some system reform.
可能跟改制有关
I heard instructor Hu said
我刚听胡教官说了
last year our school
咱们学校去年
had ordered
跟英国
torpedo boats
桑尼克罗夫特公司
from Thornycroft, a British company.
订的鱼雷艇
Now eight of them have arrived.
首批八艘已经到国内了
The 55-inch-torpedo boat
五十五英寸型鱼雷艇
is the latest model after WWI.
一战后最新式的
Yes.
对
Two petrol engines provide a cruising speed of
两台汽油发动机
34 to 42 knots
航速三十四到四十二节
with an endurance of
而且续航能力
300 nautical miles.
有三百海里
Two Whitehead Torpedoes it got.
还自带两枚白头鱼雷
Its maximum speed reaches 41 knots,
最大航速四十一节
and a firing range of
攻击时射程得有
1000...
一千
Hua Zhen,
华桢
is it 1400 or 1600?
是一千四还是一千六啊
What?
什么
What's the maximum range
我说白头鱼雷
of Whitehead Torpedoes?
最大射程是多少啊
1400.
一千四
1400 meters at max.
最大一千四百米
Last year
去年
you're the most excited one
学校说要买海岸鱼雷艇
after knowing we bought torpedo boats.
最兴奋的就是你
Do you
现在
feel like you're going
是不是感觉
to meet your girlfriend now?
要去娶老婆呀
Hua Zhen,
华桢
Yes, Sir.
到
In my office.
到我办公室来一趟
Yes, sir.
是
Coastal torpedo boats we ordered
学校订购的海岸鱼雷艇
have arrived
已经到了
at Jiangnan Shipyard in Shanghai.
上海的江南造船厂了
They will be transported
测试调试之后
to the campus after testing.
就要转到学校来
Now
现在
the task to take over torpedo boats
去接收鱼雷艇的任务
is on your Class Three.
已经交到我们三班了
Your brother told me
你哥哥跟我提过
what happened to you in Shanghai.
你在上海发生的事
The assignment
任务
is given by the Director.
是教育长亲自安排的
But if you have any concerns,
但是如果你有什么顾虑
you may request to opt out.
可以申请不参加
I can do it.
我可以参加
Nothing inconvenient?
没什么不方便吗
No,
报告教官
Sir.
没有
Then pack your luggage.
那就收拾行李吧
We'll set out tomorrow
明天出发
and come back a week later.
预计一周后返回
Yes, sir.
是
Yuansheng.
向警官
It's me, Tian Dongbao.
田冬宝
Officer Tian.
田警官
Instructor Hu.
胡教官
What's up?
什么事儿
Sir,
报告教官
I encounter a friend of mine.
我遇到了一个朋友
You have two minutes.
给你两分钟
Quick.
尽快归队
Yes, sir.
是
Let's go.
走
Officer Tian,
田警官
Why are you working at the dock?
你怎么在码头干活
I'm not a police man anymore.
我现在已经不是警察了
Just call me Dongbao.
你就叫我冬宝就行了
Don't you know
你是不是不知道
the Fourth Station has been dismissed?
四所被撤了
When did it occur?
什么时候的事儿
Not long after you left.
就在你走后没多久
We were dissolved
说是市政改革
because of some municipal reform.
大家伙儿就都散了
I got a job at the dock.
我就来码头找个差事
After all, I'm strong enough.
反正有的是力气嘛
Dongbao,
田冬宝
hurry up!
快点儿
I'm coming!
好嘞
Yuansheng,
那个 向警官
are you available
你今天晚上有没有时间
to have dinner at my home tonight?
来我家吃个饭
I can gather up
我把四所的大家伙儿
officers of the Fourth Station.
都叫上
And one more thing,
还有个事儿就是
I'm married.
我结婚了
You're married!
你结婚了
I live at
我家住在
No.5, Anren Lane,
高昌庙镇西边
on the west side of Gaochang Temple Town.
安仁弄十五号
Back to work, or I'll dock your pay.
再磨蹭扣你工钱了
One minute!
好 来了
Don't forget to come.
那个 你千万要来啊
No.5, Anren Lane,
高昌庙镇西边
on the west side of Gaochang Temple Town.
安仁弄十五号
Hurry up!
快点儿
OK.
好嘞